Francisco Pino

Houston, TX, USA 77092 +1 (407) 486 5349 franciscopino1997@gmail.

Summary

Experienced Software Engineer with strong automation development skills and background working with engineering and quality teams. Highly skilled in REST APIs, JSON, and NoSQL databases with a proven history of best-in-class development. Strong problem-solver with solid computer science fundamentals, including algorithms and data structures. Authoritative .NET Developer ready to lead full-stack software development efforts at any scale. Excels at integrating vital coding technologies such as Mobile Apps and Computer Apps.

Work Experience

Little Orbit, Senior Back End (Server Side) Engineer, Contract, Remote September 2022 – March 2023

- · Contributed to custom game design and fix previous bugs from previous work.
- · Implemented SSO Login with integration of Authentication system through server side using Custom API from different platforms such as Google, Facebook and Twitch
- · Implemented System of Twitch Drops which allow user to claim rewards after watching stream through the platform twitch and has an authentication, until finally could earn rewards into their account
- · Well developed game using C# programming language and using tools and libraries for the game
- \cdot Implemented the system of Daily Login Rewards which allows users to gain rewards through monthly events
- Implemented Database operations using MongoDB to get and add information into tables
- Using Unit test to test previous and new codes and solve issues and bugs during the process

Forty-seven Apps LLC, Lead Software Developer, Part Time, On-Site August 2022 - Today

- \cdot Contributed into different projects planification, structure, and design for Mobile Applications.
- \cdot Revision of Code added planification to be able to make multiple apps go live in different environments such as Play Store and App Store
- · Using Technologies to be able to successfully build mobile applications using SWIFT and JAVA for native applications and React-Native for cross platform
- ·Successfully added an admin panel for each platform and be able to manipulate in app data through different database such as AWS and MongoDB

Skills

- *Testing and debugging
- *Configuration management
- *Tools
 customization
- * Fluent in C, C++, C#
- *Efficient data management
- *Advanced computer programming
- *Design and development
- *Embedded systems development software
- *Testing and deployment
- *UI/UX
- *Web Developer
- *Experience designing, building, and supporting multi-layered enterprise applications using Microsoft technologies.
- *MySQL
- *MongoDB
- *Excellent communicator
- · *SOL
- *JavaScript
 expert
- ${}^* \text{Application} \\$ development

Wild Card Game, .NET Developer/Mobile Developer, Full Time, Remote January 2022 - July 2022

- · Contributed to custom game design and fix previous bugs from previous work.
- Working as DevOps and connecting through database and blockchain structures
- · Worked with Smart NFT to develop a Play to Earn game
- · Well developed game using C# programming language and using tools and libraries for the game
- \cdot Using Firebase as connection for database, MetaMask, AUTH system for the game
- using SWIFT as programming language could be able to successfully convert this application in a mobile platform

Clinic of Hope, .NET Developer/Mobile Developer, Contractor, Remote December 2021 - January 2022

- · Contributed to custom game design and fix previous bugs from previous work
- · Develop Good reusable code efficient with the latest technology.
- · Created new algorithms to be able to meet the requirements of this game for children
- · Well developed game using C# programming language and using tools and libraries for the game

Greyhound, Game Developer, Contract, Remote

September 2021 - November 2021

- · Contributed to Full Game design for a future NFT Game being a lead game developer.
- \cdot Game developer and Game designer for a private company without any other game developer and designer.
- · Using as Unity Engine to fully design and develop an online multiplayer racing game
- ·With .NET experience using C# with Microsoft Studio Framework I could fully deploy a game

Pollos Cacique (Venezuela), Software Engineer, Full Time, Remote

September, 2017 - May, 2021

- Contributed to internal development and testing standards, employing C# to improve framework efficiencies and policy standardization.
- · Improved and corrected existing software and system applications.
- \cdot $\,$ Integrated object-oriented design and development techniques into projects to support usability goals.
- · Coordinated system installations, testing, and code corrections.
- · Designed front-end and back-end solutions for test-driven development.

Degrees

Computer Science Bachelor of Science

05/2021

Full Sail University, Winter Park, FL

- *Work ethic
- *Fluent in Spanish
- *HTML, CSS, ISON
- *Experienced
 Mobile Developer
- *Android Studio and Xcode experience
- *Cocoa-pods experience
- *Python DataScientist
- *Machine Learning experienced
- *OOP (Object
 Oriented Programming)
- *Rest APIs
- *Unity EngineExpert
- *Xamarin -React Native
- *Firebase
- *Blockchain
- *NFT
- *Smart Token
- *Website
- *React and React Native
- *Blockchain
- *Solidity
- · *Metadata
- *AWS

Github

- <u>https://github.com/fpbolivar</u>

Projects

Matanoobs: Online Multiplayer Shooting

- https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.nesti.ma tanoobs

Raaise: social media

- https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.raaise.a ndroid
- https://apps.apple.com/us/app/raaise-app/id1667121707

Dalydoc: Calendar application to Schedule appointments

- https://apps.apple.com/us/app/dalydoc/id1661801278
- https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.dalydoc. android